# MANUEL MONTALVO

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a solutions-oriented Software Engineer who has experience in working in project teams to deliver full-stack applications. Detail-oriented and business-minded, I use my work experience in business operations and my training in software development to provide excellent experiences for customers.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineering Fellow

General Assembly | February 2021-May 2021

- Architect and built fully responsive front end web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, and third-party API integrations
- Developed full-stack applications and designed REST APIs with full CRUD functionality using React, JavaScript, Node.js, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, and Ruby on Rails
- Applied knowledge of key languages and computer science concepts, including algorithms, data structures, databases, and MVC pattern design to develop high-quality and maintainable code

## **Operations Intern**

Orlando Solar Bears | August 2019 - February 2020

- Facilitated 12 new season ticket sales within a 2-month period
- Provide support for the operations department (i.e. half-time, escorting V.I.P.s)
- Assist in special events ran by the Solar Bears

## **Resident Assistant**

SUNY Cobleskill August 2014 - August 2016

- Executed administrative assignments, fulfilled maintenance requests, submitted incident reports, and transfers
- Provided educational programs and paraprofessional counseling for a residence hall wing of 20 college students
- Acted as a liaison between campus residents and the Department of Residence Life

### PROJECTS

- Collaboreatery a community-based directory for restaurants focusing on price, location, and cuisine. This application is made with ReactJS, Express, MongoDB, and NodeJS.
- Campfire Full stack application with full CRUD and user authentication and authorization. Built with React, CSS, PostgresSQL, Ruby on Rails, bcrypt, and JWT.
- GitHub Finder This project is a Github profile search application made with ReactJS using the GitHub API. It utilizes context hooks for state management and follows React architecture best practices.

#### CONTACT ME:

- 7339 Burgess Drive, lake Worth,
- manuelsmontalvo@gmail.com
- www.manuelsmontalvo.com
- in www.linkedin.com/in/manuelsmontalvo
- www.github.com/manuelsmontalvo

#### SKILLS SUMMARY

- ReactIS
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript
- Ruby
- · Ruby on Rail
- MongoDB
- PostgreSQL
- Pvthon

### COMPETENCIES

- Project/Product Management
- Resource Management
- Supply-Chain Management
- Business Climate Analysis

## **EDUCATION**

<u>General Assembly</u> February 2021 - May 2021 Software Engineering Immersive

<u>University of Central Florida</u> August 2017 - December 2020 B.S.B.A. Integrated Business

Global Academic Ventures
December 2018
International Business Program